A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 3255-6261 FA739B
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Etude preliminaire sur la reforme administrative en Algerie (Reports 004569), 1965 (Box 205)
  Public administration -- Algeria; Administrative agencies -- Algeria; Political science -- Algeria; Ford Foundation. Vice President; Council For International Progress In Management (Usa) Inc
- The Marathi literary scene: Field trip to Bombay (Reports 004570), 1980 (Box 205)
  L79-90
  16 p. + appendices.
  Indic literature
- Women (Reports 004571), 1977 (Box 205)
  Memo to Robert S. Drysdale describing the work of the FF Mexico City Office in the role and status of women in Mexican society.
  L72-306.
  Women -- Mexico; Women -- Mexico -- Social conditions; Women -- Research -- Mexico; Women -- Research -- Latin America; Women in development -- Mexico; Women -- Civil rights -- Mexico; Social values -- Mexico; Social values -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. Field Office Mexico City; Ford Foundation; Office of Latin America and the Caribbean; Comunicación, Intercambio y Desarrollo Humano en América Latina
- Program of work for agriculture, Ford Foundation India, Jan. 1969-Mar. 1971. (Reports 004572) (Box 205)
  The Foundation's agricultural program in support of the Indian government is to aid in the development of India's own ability to plan and carry out effective programs of agricultural development. This document is a mechanism for integrating the diverse a,NULL,NULL,NULL,NULL,UPRA,Access may be restricted; consult Archivist.,NULL
  India program of work for agriculture
- Communications and the India Field Office: end of tour report (Reports 004573), 1970 (Box 206)
  Evaluation of the operation of the India Field Office, especially in terms of communication both within the office and to the public.
  41 p. + appendices.
  Communication in personnel management -- India; Philanthropy -- Public relations; Ford Foundation. India Field Office.
- Spain: Trip report, October 23-November 19 (Reports 004574), 1968 (Box 206)
  06200042
  Education, Higher -- Spain
- Dependent organizations, December 1970. (Reports 004575) (Box 206)
  2 p. + attachments.
  Program budgeting; Endowments -- Management; Nonprofit organizations; Ford Foundation Management
- Staff and program development in the Faculty of Agriculture, University of Ibadan (Reports 004576), 1975 (Box 206)
  7 p.: table
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Nigeria -- Planning; Education, Higher -- Nigeria -- Planning; University of Ibadan; University of Ibadan. Dept. of Agricultural Economics.
- A study in family planning communication: direct mailing (Reports 004577), 1964 (Box 206)
  Birth control -- India; Contraceptives -- India; Contraception -- India; National Institute of Family Planning (India)
- Public corporations: management problems in Tanzania, Kenya, and Ghana (Reports 004578), 1974 (Box 206)
  Economic development -- Tanzania; Economic development -- Kenya; Economic development -- Ghana; Economic development -- Case studies; Corporations -- Tanzania; Corporations -- Kenya; Corporations -- Ghana
- A survey of international student activities at two West Coast Universities (Reports 004579), 1954 (Box 206)
  Bibliography and appendix included.
  94 p. + appendices
  American students -- Foreign countries; Students, Foreign -- United States; International relations; Student exchange programs -- United States; Stanford University; University of California, Berkeley
- A program for rice production and research for Algeria 1973. (Reports 004580) (Box 206)
  24 p. + appendices: tables
  Rice -- Algeria; Rice -- Research -- Algeria; Rice trade -- Algeria; Rice -- Yields; Ford Foundation
- Survey for the in-plant advisory service of the West Pakistan Management Association (Reports 004581), 1969 (Box 206, Reel R-9302)
  Industrial management -- Pakistan; Small business -- Pakistan; Industries -- Pakistan
- An analysis of the rate of return on investment in business education in East Pakistan (Reports 004582), 1970 (Box 206)
  12 p. + appendix
  Business education -- Bangladesh; Industrial management -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Bangladesh -- Evaluation; Education, Higher -- Bangladesh; Business education -- Bangladesh; Educational assistance -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation Program Development -- Bangladesh; Dacca Polytechnic Institute (Bangladesh)
- Report on Training Associate Assignment in Malaysia (Reports 004583), 1969 (Box 206)
  Memo to Eugene Staples.
  Training Associate Assignment in Malaysia
  Technical assistance -- Malaysia; Educational assistance -- Malaysia; Public administration -- Malaysia; Ford Foundation. Training Associate Program; Ford Foundation. Program associates; Ford Foundation
- Management education and training in the Arab world: a review of issues, problems, and possible solutions (Reports 004584), 1976 (Box 206)
  A paper presented at the Arab League, Arab Organization of Administrative Sciences Conference on Management Training in the Civil Services of the Arab world, Tunis, February 19-27, 1976. -- T.p.
  Economic development -- Arab countries; Management -- Study and teaching -- Arab countries; Industrial management -- Arab countries; Executives -- Training of -- Arab countries; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Report of the North African Review Team on the Population Council/Ford Foundation work on population and family planning in Morocco (Reports 004585), 1972 (Box 206)
  36 p. + appendices.
  Population and family planning in Morocco
  Birth control -- Morocco; Contraception -- Morocco; Contraceptives -- Morocco -- Statistics; Population assistance -- Morocco; Social sciences -- Research -- Morocco; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Report on demographic work in Algeria of special interest to the Population Council and the Ford Foundation (Reports 004586), 1972 (Box 206)
  Demographic work in Algeria ...
  Urbanization -- Algeria; Urbanization -- Africa, North; Economic development -- Algeria; Economic development -- Africa, North; Economic assistance -- Algeria; Ford Foundation; Population Council
- Supplementary report: the French connection 1972 /Ronald Freedman. (Reports 004587) (Box 206)
  Includes appendix. Population Council/Ford Foundation North African Review Team supplementary report.
  The French connection
  Birth control -- Africa, North; Public health -- Africa, North; Public health -- Africa; Public health -- Study and teaching -- France; Ford Foundation; École nationale de la santé publique (France); Centre international de l'enfance, Paris; MFPF (Mouvement francais pour le planning familial) (Paris)
- The demographic French connection (Reports 004588), 1972 (Box 206)
  Population research -- Africa, French-speaking; Population research -- Africa, North; Population research -- Algeria; Population research -- Morocco; Ford Foundation; Population Council
- Algerian wheat problems (Reports 004589), 1970 (Box 206)
  Wheat -- Algeria; Wheat -- Yields -- Algeria; Ford Foundation. Field Office Tunis; Ford Foundation. Africa, North
- The urban infrastructure program (Reports 004590), 1985 (Box 206)
  This report is located in IR-6, as a part of 83-517, as of 10-85.
  United States and International Affairs Program/Urban Poverty program
  Urban renewal
- Economic and marketing factors in animal production (Reports 004591), 1968 (Box 206)
  Prepared for Second World Conference on Animal Production, University of Maryland, July 17, 1968.
  PAPER Conference (1968 Nov. 6-8: Bogota, Colombia)
  Agricultural development projects -- Latin America
- Research on race and ethnicity: reports on federal (and some other) agencies, August 1973. (Reports 004592) (Box 207)
  Reports from FF staff members on research performed by federal agencies, independent research institutes, and research institutes of the United Nations on the subject of race and ethnicity.
  Ethnic relations -- Research; Ethnicity -- United States -- Research; Minorities -- United States -- Research; African Americans -- United States -- Research; Research institutes -- United States; Ford Foundation
- Final report on the Ford Foundation building, June 1970. (Reports 004594) (Box 207)
  New York (N.Y.); Historic buildings -- New York (N.Y.); Architecture -- New York (N.Y.); Ford Foundation
- Evaluation of independent art schools receiving Ford Foundation scholarship grants 1963-1971 (Reports 004595), 1969 (Box 207)
  118 p.: tables -- 32 cm.
  Art schools -- Evaluation; Art -- Study and teaching -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Arts
- Re-examination of India's administrative system with special reference to administration of government's industrial and commercial enterprises (Reports 004596), 1959 (Box 207)
  PA54-110.
  Public administration -- India
- The Ford Foundation in Egypt 1975: where do we go from here?, June 1975. (Reports 004597) (Box 207)
  A Cairo Office Staff document.
  Philanthropy -- Egypt; Agricultural assistance -- Egypt; Economic assistance -- Egypt; Ford Foundation Program Development -- Egypt -- Planning; International Center for Agricultural Research in the Dry Areas
- Slicing it once again: some observations for discussion (Reports 004598), 1975 (Box 207)
  Draft memorandum to all professional staff.
  Charity organization -- Middle East -- Management; Charity organization -- Middle East -- Administration; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation
- Some observations on the status and future of the Agricultural Economics Program (Reports 004599), 1975 (Box 207)
  Memo to Courtney Nelson.
  07490830
  11 p. + table.
  Agricultural Economics Program
  Agriculture -- Research
- How thin can we slice it?: some reflections on the Foundation's geographic spread of activities in the Middle East 1975-1976? (Reports 004600) (Box 207)
  Philanthropy -- Middle East
- Spread of the Middle East Program (Reports 004601), 1975 (Box 207)
  Memo to all professional staff.
  Middle East Program
  Economic development -- Middle East; Social sciences -- Middle East -- Research; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Middle East; Education -- Middle East; Linguists -- Middle East; Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Ford Foundation; International Center for Agricultural Research in the Dry Areas
- Interim report on retrospective language survey (Reports 004602), 1974 (Box 207)
  International Division/Office of the Vice President/Education & Research
  07190366
  20 p. + attachments.
  PAPER Conference (1973 Dec. 10-11: New York, N.Y.)
  ESL (English as a second language); Language and languages
- Proposed linguistic institutes in the Middle East (Reports 004603), 1972 (Box 207)
  Discussion paper.
  10 p. + appendices: tables
  Linguists -- Middle East; Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Middle East
- Middle East visit (Reports 004604), 1973 (Box 207)
  Memo to David E. Bell.
  Background paper for program discussions
  Arab-Israeli conflict; Economic development -- Arab countries; Industrialization -- Arab countries; Social sciences -- Arab countries -- Research; Education -- Arab countries; Industrial management -- Arab countries; Language and linguistics -- Arab countries
- Reflections on "Assisting educational cultural development" and the Cali meeting (Reports 004605), 1974 (Box 207)
  Memo to F.C. Ward and O. Harkavy.
  Language and languages -- Arab countries; Social sciences -- Arab countries -- Research; Industrial management -- Arab countries; Ford Foundation
- Towards a Foundation strategy for the Sudan (Reports 004606), 1975 (Box 207)
  Education, Higher -- Sudan; Economic development -- Sudan; Agriculture -- Sudan -- Research; International relations -- Sudan; Language and languages -- Sudan; Ford Foundation. East Africa Office; Ford Foundation; University of Khartoum
- Aspects of programming in the Middle East, March 1975. (Reports 004607) (Box 207)
  Programming in the Middle East
  Economic conditions -- Arab countries; Economic assistance -- Arab countries; Labor supply -- Arab countries; Natural resources -- Arab countries; Industrialization -- Arab countries; Philanthropy -- Arab countries; Charity organization -- Arab countries; Ford Foundation
- Report on Gulf Technical College (Reports 004608), 1973 (Box 207)
  Background of and suggestions for Gulf Technical College.
  Gulf Technical College
  Technical education -- United Kingdom; Gulf Technical College
- Management training in Bahrain: Middle East facilities (Reports 004609), 1973 (Box 207)
  Plans for management training by the Bahrain Government.
  Executives -- Training of -- Bahrain; Management -- Study and teaching -- Bahrain
- Report on trip to Bahrain (via Kuwait) (Reports 004610), 1976 (Box 207)
  Memo to Robert H. Edwards.
  Housing -- Arab countries; Housing -- Bahrain; Housing policy -- Bahrain; Households -- Bahrain; Housing -- Kuwait
- Arab higher education: a regional analysis 1974 (Reports 004611) (Box 207)
  Education, Higher -- Arab countries
- Establishing an Arab institute for the study of higher education: a position paper (Reports 004612), 1976 (Box 207)
  Education, Higher -- Arab countries -- Curricula; Education, Higher -- Arab countries -- Administration; Occupational training -- Arab countries; Teachers -- Training of -- Arab countries
- Visit to Kuwait: December 14-18 (Reports 004613), 1973 (Box 207)
  Industrialization -- Kuwait; Pollution -- Kuwait; Public health -- Kuwait; Marine pollution -- Persian Gulf Coast (Persian Gulf States); Maʻhad al-Kuwayt lil-Abḥāth al-ʻIlmīyah
- Use of high level manpower in the Arab world (Reports 004614), 1976 (Box 207)
  Labor supply -- Arab countries; Occupational training -- Arab countries; Philanthropy -- Arab countries; Charity organization -- Arab countries; Educational assistance -- Arab countries; Social planning -- Arab countries
- Higher education and development in the Arab world: a study project 1974 (Reports 004615) (Box 207)
- Memorandum on the Akrawi proposal (Reports 004616), 1973 (Box 207)
  Education, Higher -- Arab countries; Education, Higher -- Research -- Arab countries; Universities and colleges -- Arab countries; University cooperation -- Arab countries
- The cognitive-developmental approach to moralization (Reports 004617), 1974 (Box 207)
  Outline of the cognitive-developmental approach to socialization as proposed by Lawrence Kohlberg discussing moralization.
  7 p. + tables.
  Constructivism (Education); Moral development; Socialization
- The Foundation's Latin American and Caribbean program: a review and a look ahead, March 1972. (Reports 004618) (Box 207)
  title sufficient as abstract.
  79 p. + appendices: ill., maps, tables, chart -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Caribbean Area -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Another lens for viewing development (Reports 004619), 1976 (Box 207)
  Community development -- Middle East; Poverty -- Middle East; Social change -- Middle East; Social planning -- Middle East
- A review of numerical indices of school desegregation (Reports 004620), 1977 (Box 208)
  PA64-508.
  23 p. + appendix.
  School integration -- United States -- Statistics; Education -- United States; Educational equalization -- United States
- An Arabic APL computing system (Reports 004621), 1974 (Box 208)
  8 p.: ill.
  Computer science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Arab countries; Computer systems -- Study and teaching -- Arab countries; Programming languages (Electronic computers); APL (Computer program language); APL2 (Computer program language)
- Report to the Ford Foundation concerning consultation with the Lebanese government on revision of the intensive training course sponsored by the Civil Service Board for diplomatic officers from the Arab states (Reports 004622), 1972 (Box 208)
  Intensive training course ...
  Diplomats -- Arab countries; Diplomats -- Training of -- Arab countries; International relations; Diplomacy -- Study and teaching -- Arab countries; Lebanon Civil Service Board
- Final report on assignments (Reports 004623), 1974 (Box 208)
  7 p. + attachments.
  Taxation -- Lebanon; Tax administration and procedure -- Lebanon; Income tax -- Lebanon; Lebanon Civil Service Board
- Ministry of Finance Project, Lebanon, February 1-August 30, 1969: terminal report (Reports 004624) (Box 208)
  Ministry of Finance Project
  Finance, Public -- Lebanon; Public administration -- Lebanon; Technical assistance -- Lebanon; Occupational training -- Lebanon; Lebanon. Wizārat al-Mālīyah
- Elites and national development in the Arabian peninsula: Political culture and foreign relations 1975? (Reports 004625) (Box 208)
  Tribes -- Arabian Peninsula -- Political aspects
- Report on the advisory mission undertaken by Mr. Hamid Ammar to AFESD from 28th November to 11 (Reports 004626), 1975 (Box 208)
  Memo to M. Mansour
  Philanthropy -- Arab countries; Social change -- Arab countries; Education -- Arab countries; Literacy -- Arab countries; Public health -- Arab countries; Technical assistance -- Arab countries; Research -- Arab countries; Human capital -- Arab countries; Ford Foundation; Arab Fund for Economic and Social Development; United Nations Development Programme
- The role of foundations in manpower and human resource development (Reports 004627), 1969 (Box 208)
  "Delivered at the Third Annual Summer Manpower Research Institute, June 2-6, 1969, Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa". -- T.p.
  29 p. + appendix: tables
  Foundations -- Charitable contributions -- Statistics; Charities -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Education -- United States; Human capital -- United States; Ford Foundation
- Africa law programs 1973? (Reports 004628) (Box 208)
  07200236
  Philanthropy -- Africa; Law -- Africa; International Legal Center
- Public administration (Reports 004629), 1970 (Box 208)
  L72-236
  16 p.: tables
  Public administration -- Africa, Southern; Occupational training -- Africa, Southern; Technical assistance -- Africa, Southern; Civil service -- Africa, Southern; Human capital -- Africa, Southern; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Development planning south of the Sahara 1972 (Reports 004630) (Box 208)
  The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York
  Support for programs in East Asian studies.
  10, 9 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Central planning -- Africa, Sub-Saharan; Economic development -- Africa, Sub-Saharan; Ford Foundation. International Division Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.); Ford Foundation. Africa, Sub-Saharan
- Future of women's programming in Nicaragua (Reports 004631), 1980 (Box 208)
  Memo to Peter Cleaves.
  Women's programming in Nicaragua
  Women -- Social conditions -- Nicaragua; Women -- Employment -- Nicaragua; Women executives -- Training of -- Nicaragua; Occupational training -- Nicaragua; Ford Foundation; AMNLAE (Association)
- Social class and the definition of the Cuban nation (Reports 004632), 1969 (Box 208)
  Social classes -- Cuba
- Toward a policy for Foundation assistance to Latin American education in the seventies (Reports 004633), 1971 (Box 208)
  27 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Educational assistance -- Latin America; Education -- Latin America; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. International Division Conference (1971 Oct. 25-29: New Delhi, India); Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Poverty: Changing social stratification, 196? (Reports 004634), 1960 (Box 208)
  Poverty -- United States; Social classes -- United States; Social status -- United States; African Americans -- Social conditions; Segregation -- United States; Equality -- United States; Ethics -- United States; Social mobility -- United States
- A three-year planning paper for agriculture 1971-1973 (Reports 004635) (Box 208)
  A very preliminary draft.
  iii, 91 p.: tables
  Agriculture -- Brazil; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Brazil; Agricultural development projects -- Brazil -- Evaluation; Grants-in-aid -- Brazil -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Field Office Brazil
- Comments on programs on agricultural economics programs in Argentina (Reports 004636), 1970 (Box 208)
  Agricultural economics programs in Argentina
  Agriculture -- Argentina; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Argentina; Agricultural development projects -- Argentina; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Argentina -- Curricula
- An evaluation of the Ford Foundation Agricultural Economics Program in Argentina 1965? (Reports 004637) (Box 208)
  Agricultural Economics Program in Argentina
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Study and teaching -- Argentina; Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Argentina
- Black Africa in 1973: the search for equality in an unequal world (Reports 004638) (Box 208)
  Council on foreign relations;Discussion group on African development (meeting of May 10, 1973) -- T.p.
  Self-determination, National -- Africa, Sub-Saharan; National liberation movements -- Africa, Sub-Saharan; International relations; International organization
- Bank Melli Iran assignment: end of mission report (Reports 004639), 1959 (Box 208)
  05800079
  7, 2 p.
  Banks and banking -- Iran -- Management; Banking law -- Iran; Monetary policy -- Iran; Ford Foundation. Near East and Africa
- Population in the 1980s, December 1979: Information Paper (Reports 004640-001) (Box 208)
  Cataloged by D.Merkle;Electronic content available in SharePoint Archives collection.
  Overpopulation; Birth control; Birth control -- Research; Overpopulation -- Sociological aspects; Ford Foundation
- Population in the 1980s, December 1979: Supplementary Charts and Tables (Reports 004640-002)
  46 p.: tables,charts
- Ford Foundation programs for women (Reports 004641), 1979 (Box 208)
  An information paper for the Board of Trustees.
  National Affairs/Education and Public Policy (EPP)/International Division
  Women -- Social conditions; Women -- Education; Women -- Employment; Sex discrimination; Ford Foundation
- American studies abroad, with particular reference to the American Council of Learning Societies program (Reports 004642), 1969 (Box 208)
  06990154
  217 p.
  Universities and colleges; Americanists; Ford Foundation; American Council of Learned Societies
- Claims on general reserves (Reports 004643), 1978 (Box 208)
  Memorandum to Board of Trustees, dated November 17, 1978.
  6 p. + annex: tables -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ford Foundation. Office of the President; Ford Foundation
- Nuclear power issues: a Foundation strategy (Reports 004644), 1975 (Box 209)
  National Affairs/Research & Education
  Nuclear energy -- United States; Nuclear fuels -- Safety measures -- United States; Energy development -- Environmental aspects -- Research -- United States; Environmental policy -- United States; Ford Foundation. Resources and the Environment.
- Women in development: final consultancy report, August 27-September 10 (Reports 004645), 1976 (Box 209)
  Memorandum to Lincoln Chen and Bill Fuller. Sketches changes which have occurred in Bangladesh since April 1 report, tasks completed, and activities to be followed up.
  07690804
  Women -- Bangladesh -- Social conditions; Women -- Bangladesh -- Economic conditions
- Food, employment, and the role of women in Indonesia (Reports 004647), 1978 (Box 209)
  Women's rights -- Indonesia
- The first amendment budget: information paper, October 1972. (Reports 004648) (Box 209)
  PA73-801.
  Freedom of the press -- United States; Mass media -- Law and legislation -- United States; Mass media and culture -- United States; Mass media and public opinion -- United States; Television broadcasting policy -- United States; Ford Foundation